Juan Camilo Flórez Vanegas

jcflorezv@unal.edu.co | jcamilo.co | +57 322 326 67 29

EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE COLOMBIA

Bs. Computer Science 2016 - 2022 | Bogotá Cum. GPA: 4.3 / 5.0

LINKS

HTTPS:// jcamilo.co LinkedIn:// VanJFlorez GitHub:// VanJFlorez GitLab:// VanJFlorez

CERTS

- B2 English Certification (IELTS)
- C1 English Certification (EF)
- Machine Learning with Big Data
- Convolutional Neural Networks
- Automate Stuff with Python
- Econometrics (University)
- Micro and Macroeconomics (University)
- Economic History (University)
- * Some entries are linked to the certificates.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Java • C /++ • Javascript • TypeScript •SQL • CSS • Python • Ruby • Bash •Batch

Frameworks/SDK/Libraries

• Spring Boot • Quarkus • RubyOnRails • Django • EJB JSF JPA (Hibernate)
PrimeFaces • React/Material-UI •
Bootstrap • Android SDK • NumPy •
Scikit-Learn • Pandas • Boost C++ •
KNIME • Spark

Tools/Protocols

• Git • Kubernetes • Azure • Docker • ElasticSearch • Jaeger • OpenShift • Azure DevOps • Apache Flink • Apache Kafka • Apache Flume • Apache Camel • JUnit • JMS • Mockito • Visual Studio • Tensorflow • SOAP UI • GNU-Linux • MongoDB • Oracle Database 11g • SQLite • PostgreSQL • MySQL • Power Designer • Virtual Box • Linux Servers • Audacity • Moodle • Maven • Gradle • SSH clients • Heroku • Jenkins • Google Compute Engine • TortoiseSVN • 上TEX

Architectures/Methodologies

• Microservices • REST • Web Services • SOAP • DevOps (Azure) • Pipelining • Scrum • Good Practices (SOLID, Modularity, Design Patterns)

PROFILE

Computer Systems Engineer with 5 years of experience in Software Engineering and Development. Professional with proficient skills in Mathematics, Software Development, Software Architecture and Software Design. Highly motivated by reaching goals and measurements. Agile learner. Up-to-date with State of the Art in software construction and implementation techniques. He is an Engineer committed with organizations mission statements, with a great sense of responsibility, commitment and good teamwork. Can speak English and Portuguese.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

CREDERA STREAM PROCESSING / MICROSERVICES / COMPUTER GRAPHICS

SENIOR JAVA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nov 2021 - Current | United States (remote)

 $(\textit{Tools/Tech. stack}) \ \textit{C/C++}, \ \textit{Blender}, \ \textit{Kafka}, \ \textit{Java} \ 11, \ \textit{AWS}, \ \textit{Postgres}, \ \textit{Spring Boot}, \ \textit{Kubernetes}$

- Re-implementation of Java7 legacy monoliths to Java11 microservices.
- Write several *Kafka* consumer-producers for the user-engagement streaming pipelines.
- Blender (C/C++) source code reverse engineering in order to understand and replicate Ghost UI for desktop applications.
- Build scripting with CMake.
- Develop a complete template file for work with Vulkan (C/C++) API.
- Microservices development with Spring Boot.
- Custom libraries development for microservices and ERP processing units that share the same business logic.
- Member of DE&I committee (marketing pillar).

CLARO BIGDATA PROCESSING / MICROSERVICES

JAVA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Feb 2020 - Nov 2021 | S Brazil (remote)

(Tools/Tech. stack) Java 11, Apache Flume - Flink - Kafka - Camel, MongoDB, Spring Boot, OpenShift

- Microservices development with Spring Boot, Quarkus and Django. Some examples can be seen **here**.
- Big Data processing components using Apache Kafka, Flink, Flume and Camel.
- Batch Scripts and Java programs to automate Docker images builds and storage within Docker Hub cloud registry.
- Deployments in Openshift Container Platform pre-production environments. This includes scripts for builds and image stress tests.
- Provide mentorship for Junior and entry-level developers.
- Take part as technical expert in 'MiClaro App' UI enhancements project.

ZYOS BACKEND MONOLITH DEVELOPER / SERVER SIDE UI RENDERING

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020 | — Colombia

(Tools/Tech. stack) EJB, JSF, Primefaces, JPA (Hibernate), Angular 9, JavaScript (ES6), Maven, Git, Apache TomCat

- Made improvements to *Edificios Davivienda* App business core features.
- Responsive front-end implementation and some styling improvements. Several JavaScript components (notifications, ratings, snackbars) to improve the user experience.
- Backend software development to *Mi Vivienda BCP* App in order to boost and correct bugs in execution edge cases. New functionalities to the overall application. *Edificios Davivienda* available **here** and *Mi Vivienda BCP* available **here**.

CENTRO DE PENSAMIENTO UNAL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018 | Bogotá

(Tools/Tech. stack) Ruby, RubyOnRails, NGinX, PostgresSQL, Debian-Linux, Moodle, PHP, SSH, Heroku, Google Compute Engine, Git, Docker, Rancker

- Online course implementation with Moodle (available **here**) and a forum web application for that course with Thredded (available **here**). Full repository **here**.

GRUPO SEPRO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018 | Bogotá

(Tools/Tech. stack) Python, Django, JavaScript, ExpressJS, Gunicorn, Apache HTTP Server, Git, VSCode, MySQL, Heroku

- Designed and implemented a survey information system that computes statistics and measurements. This survey system was used to evaluate the behavior and performance of Avocado and Sugar Cane derivatives supply chains from Cauca to Bogota.
- Coordinated a team of 3 undergraduate students to achieve the project goals. Two of them worked in software development and the another one work in QA. Available here.